Guide to the Martha Bradstreet Papers 1774-1868 MS 72
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: Legal Documentation. Materials regarding lawsuits, 1774-1856, undated
  - Subseries IV.C. Court Documents, 1819-1835, undated
    Worthy of note would be the fact that not only did Martha lose her various cases, she actually owed money on several occasions. This is evidenced by an 1825 indenture which states that Martha owed money to Josiah Meiss and to John S. Tillinghast. Later, in 1824 she owed money to Henry McKinstry, Additson Porter and Samuel L Penfield as described in the Bill of Complaint above. An undated document from the land office pertains to an offer to give Martha land if she drops suits for 1000 acres. This was unsigned and the wording appears to have been terminated before completion.
    - Circuit Court - MB and James Jackson vs. John Stiles and Malcom McKenyon (tenants), 1819-1824 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Assignment of Judgment between Josiah Meiss and John L. Tillinghast, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - MB's Memorials. Attempts to Remove Judge Conkling from Case, 1825-1840 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Affidavit submitted by MB to have court records authenticated., 1830 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - District Court's Dismissal of Suits, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Supreme Court opinion of MB vs Henry Huntington, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bill of Exceptions. MB vs Alexander Johnson, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bill of Complaint: Sarah Mary Anne Bradstreet vs Philip Jeremiah Schuyler and others, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Land office offer to give MB land if she drops suits for 1000 acres, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Subseries IV.D. Attorney POA, Bills, 1791-1856
    Arranged chronologically. This subseries includes a couple of grants of Power of Attorney in addition to billing statements for services rendered. The Granting of Power of Attorney from John Jackson and his wife to Edward Bradstreet is dated 1856, late in the collection. The earliest item in this subseries would be a Schedule B copy of the Power of Attorney granted by the Duke of Grafton to John Watts in 1791. In this subseries, one would also find legal court fees, most likely for the copies of wills Martha had made when she was over in London. Lastly, there is a bill for legal services E. G. Smith performed for Martha Codd.
    - Power of Attorney from Duke of Grafton to John Watts, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Edward Bell's Bill re: E. G. Smith's account against Mrs. Codd, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Court of Canterbury: Consulting and Legal Fees for Elizabeth Livius and Martha Bradstreet (d. 1782), 1818 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Power of Attorney from John Jackson to Edward Bradstreet, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series V: Miscellaneous: Hotel, Calling Cards, Religious Documents, 1815-1868, undated
  Arranged chronologically. Included in this series are various "calling cards" from friends and acquaintances, an invitation for a visit, a hotel bill from the Talbot Inn in London, where Martha spent much time in 1815 and a note from the Liverpool Post office. There are also two religious lectures including "An Early Marriage Dower" by Richard Scott of Providence from 1868 as well as a lecture given by Benjamin Scott in London dated 1866. These two documents are the latest items in the entire collection.
  - Note from Liverpool Post office, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Religious Lectures, 1866-1868 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hotel Bill - Talbot Inn, London, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Calling Cards, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)